Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Walter Henry Judd papers
1922-1988
85003
Hoover Institution Archives
273 manuscript boxes, 24 oversize boxes, 25 envelopes, 10 motion picture film reels, 19 phonorecords (152.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, minutes, statements, press releases, notes, printed matter, and audio-visual material relating to American domestic politics and foreign policy, anti-communist movements, the Chinese Civil War, American foreign policy towards China, the question of United States and United Nations recognition of China, and aid to Chinese refugees. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Judd, Walter Henry, 1898-1994.
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1898 September 25 Born, Rising City, Nebraska
1923 M.D., University of Nebraska
1925-1926 Medical missionary, Nanking, China
1926-1931 Medical missionary, Shaowu, Fukien, China
1934-1938 Medical missionary, Fenchow, Shansi, China
1938-1940 Lecturer on foreign policy
1941-1942 Physician and surgeon, Minneapolis, Minnesota
1943-1963 U.S. Congressman, Fifth Minnesota District
1950 and 1958 U.S. Delegate to World Health Organization assemblies
1951 U.S. Delegate, First Consultative Assembly of the Council of Europe
1957 U.S. Delegate to the United Nations
1964-1970 Radio commentator, Washington Report on the Air, sponsored by the American Security Council
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals.; Committee of One Million.; United Nations--China.; United States. Congress. House.; Anti-communist movements.; Audiotapes.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History--Civil War, 1945-1949.; China.; Communism.; International relief.; Moving-pictures.; Phonorecords.; Refugees.; Statesmen--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1948-1988 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, certificates, financial material, printed material, reports, speeches, press releases, newsletters, biographical material, and trip material. Arranged by form.
  - General, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Biographical sketch, business card, and correspondence relating to the disposition of Dr. Judd's papers.
  - Articles, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Printed material and correspondence.
  - Awards, 1955-1988 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Press release, clippings, certificate, list, newsletter, and miscellany.
  - Memberships, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Correspondence and miscellany relating to the Cosmos Club.
  - Sponsorships, 1963-1983 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Primarily correspondence.
  - Trip material
    - Western United States, 1953 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Middle and Far East, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 7-13, Box-folder 2: 1)
      Correspondence (includes Chester Bowles, Henry Cabot Lodge, and other State Department officials, various officials of foreign governments, and Wolf Ladejinsky), clippings and other printed material (including a pamphlet relating to the strategic hamlet program in Vietnam), speeches, miscellany, and reports (including development projects in India and Laos, the military situation in Korea, communist strategy in South Vietnam, and a presentation by Chen Cheng to the Ninth National Congress of the Kuomintang).
    - Latin America, England, Vietnam, the Far East and Africa, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1944-1984 (Box 2-32)
  General correspondence of Walter Judd, arranged alphabetically, but including major subsections arranged by date and by state (much of the latter relates to arrangements for speaking engagements). Correspondence relating to China is located in that series, and correspondence with constituents is filed in the CONGRESSIONAL FILE.
  - General
    - Invitations, circa 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Requests to serve on committees, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Alphabetical
      - A-E (Box-folder 2: 5-9)
      - F-Q (Box-folder 3: 1-12)
      - R-Z (Box-folder 4: 1-6)
    - Chronological
      - 1945-1966 (Box-folder 4: 7-9)
      - 1967-1971 (Box-folder 5: 1-4)
      - 1972-1979 (Box-folder 6: 1-4)
    - Family, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - States
      This material primarily relates to speaking arrangements, especially in later years, but it also includes other miscellaneous subjects as well.
      - Alabama, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - Alaska, 1961-1977 (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - Arizona, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - Arkansas, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - California, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - California, 1961-circa 1970 (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
      - California, circa 1966-1984 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
      - Colorado, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Connecticut, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - Delaware, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 10: 1)
      - District of Columbia, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 10: 2-4)
      - Florida, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 10: 5)
      - Florida, 1965-1984 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Georgia, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - Hawaii, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - Idaho, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - Illinois, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 11: 5)
      - Illinois, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
      - Illinois, 1966-1980 (Box-folder 13: 1-3)
      - Indiana, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - Indiana, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
      - Iowa, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - Iowa, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Kansas, 1961-1980 (Box-folder 15: 2-3)
      - Kentucky, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 15: 4)
      - Louisiana, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 16: 1)
      - Maine, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 16: 2)
      - Maryland, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 16: 3)
      - Massachusetts, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 16: 4-5)
      - Michigan, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
      - Minnesota, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 17: 3)
      - Minnesota, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
      - Minnesota, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Mississippi, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 19: 2)
      - Missouri, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 19: 3-4)
      - Montana, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - Nebraska, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 20: 2)
      - Nevada, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - New Hampshire, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 20: 4)
      - New Jersey, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 20: 5)
      - New Mexico, 1961-1980 (Box-folder 21: 1)
      - New York, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 21: 2-4)
      - New York, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 22: 1-3)
      - North Carolina, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 22: 4)
      - North Dakota, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Ohio, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 23: 2-4)
      - Oklahoma, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 24: 1)
      - Oregon, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 24: 2)
      - Pennsylvania, 1961-circa 1964 (Box-folder 24: 3-4)
      - Pennsylvania, circa 1963-1982 (Box-folder 25: 1-3)
      - Rhode Island, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 25: 4)
      - South Carolina, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 25: 5)
      - South Dakota, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - Tennessee, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 26: 2)
      - Texas, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 26: 3-5)
      - Texas, 1966-1983 (Box-folder 27: 1)
      - Utah, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 27: 2)
      - Vermont, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 27: 3)
      - Virginia, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 27: 4-5)
      - Washington, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      - West Virginia, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 28: 2)
      - Wisconsin, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 28: 3)
      - Wisconsin, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - Wyoming, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    Includes material relating to Korea.
  - American Federation of Labor/Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 29: 4)
    Primarily relates to the Free Trade Union Committee; includes letters from Matthew Woll and Jay Lovestone and printed material.
  - Baarslag, Karl, 1973 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Benson, Ezra Taft, 1956 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Blackmun, Harry, 1974 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    Includes printed material relating to China.
  - Brownfeld, Allan, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Buckley, James, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 29: 10)
    Includes a statement.
  - Buckley, William F., 1967-1981 (Box-folder 29: 11)
    Includes printed material.
  - Burger, Warren, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Bush, George, 1972 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Butz, Earl, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Carter, James Earl, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Crane, Philip, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 29: 16)
  - DeJaegher, Raymond, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 29: 17)
  - Dillon, Douglas, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Dobriansky, Lev, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 29: 19)
  - Dole, Robert, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 29: 20)
  - Douglas, William O., 1961 (Box-folder 29: 21)
  - Dulles, Allen, 1948-1962 (Box-folder 29: 22)
    Includes a memorandum on the World Anti-Communist League.
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1944-1958 (Box-folder 29: 23)
    Includes speeches and correspondence with Cyrus Eaton, David Rowe, and others.
  - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 29: 24)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1947-1969 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    Includes correspondence with others.
  - Emmet, Christopher, 1945-1970 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    Includes material relating to China.
  - Fifield, James W., Jr., 1955-1970 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Ford, Gerald and Betty, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1962-1984 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Graham, Billy, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Grew, Joseph, 1950 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Groves, Leslie R., 1951-1952 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Henderson, Loy, 1960-1974 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Herter, Christian A. and Mary, 1949-1980 (Box-folder 30: 10)
    Includes related material and a letter relating to the International Cooperation Administration in Iran.
  - Hill, Robert C., 1958-1972 (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 30: 12)
    Includes printed article and seminar (?) notes.
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1950-1976 (Box-folder 30: 13)
    Includes related material.
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 30: 15)
    Includes correspondence with others and related material.
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 1945-1978 (Box-folder 30: 16)
  - Hunter, Edward, 1954-1975 (Box-folder 30: 17)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963-1970 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Kennedy, John, 1962?-1963 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Kleindienst, Richard, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Lasky, Victor, 1954 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Laubach, Frank C., 1957-1968 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Lewis, Hobart, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Lewis, John, 1951 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Liebman, Marvin, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 31: 8)
    See also: Committee of One Million, Aid to Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, and American Chilean Council.
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1955-1959 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Lodge, John D., 1951-1959 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Luce, Henry R., Clare Boothe, and Henry III, 1944-1984 (Box-folder 31: 11)
    Includes material relating to China, statements and other material.
  - MacArthur, Douglas and Jean, 1949-1984 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1949-1968 (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Motley, Arthur R., 1962-1968 (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Murrow, Edward R., 1953 (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1952-1984 (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Nygaard, Harlan, 1945-1958 (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Peale, Norman Vincent, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 31: 18)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 31: 19)
  - Rhee, Syngman, 1943-1961 (Box-folder 31: 20)
    Includes memorandum of a meeting with Dr. Judd and related material.
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 31: 21)
  - Rogers, William P., 1969-1972 (Box-folder 31: 22)
    Includes notes for a meeting (?).
  - Roosevelt, Franklin and Eleanor, 1943 (Box-folder 31: 23)
  - Rowe, David, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 31: 24)
  - Rozek, Edward J., 1970-1976 (Box-folder 31: 25)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1950-1976 (Box-folder 31: 26)
  - Stassen, Harold, 1945-1958 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Teller, Edward, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Thomas, Lowell, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945-1973 (Box-folder 32: 4)
    Includes material on China.
  - Utley, Freda, 1948-1959 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Wallace, DeWitt, 1964-1976 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Wolfe, Ella and Bertram, 1974 (Box-folder 32: 7)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1923-circa 1982 (Box 32-61)
  Broadcast transcripts, newsletters, drafts, typecripts, and printed copies of speeches and writings with related correspondence, notes, and printed material. Transcripts of congressional debates and insertions of material in the Congressional Record by Dr. Judd have not been sorted by subject but arranged as general subsections. Arranged chronologically, thereunder by subject.
  - General
    - Walter Judd: Chronicles of a Statesman, Edward J. Rozek (Ed.) (Box-folder 32: 8)
      Book of speeches and statements with comments by Dr. Judd.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 32: 9)
        Primarily arrangements for speeches; includes Walter Hickel.
      - Agents, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 32: 10-12)
    - Schedules, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 32: 13)
    - Schedules, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 33: 1-2)
  - Fragments and undated material
    Includes clippings.
    - General (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Missionary work, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    Printed copies and a typescript.
  - "A Philosophy of Life That Works,", 1932 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    Printed copies.
  - Asia and China, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    Letter, typescripts, printed copies, and congressional testimony transcripts.
  - 1942
    - General (Box-folder 33: 8)
      Printed copies, interview, typescript, and clippings relating to Dr. Judd's congressional campaign.
    - "Behind the Conflict in the Pacific,", February 25 (Box-folder 33: 9)
      Typescript and clippings.
  - 1943
    - General
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 33: 10)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record of material by others (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Asia, Japan, and China (Box-folder 33: 12)
      - General
        Correspondence and a clipping.
      - "How Can We Win in the Pacific?,", February 25
        Printed copy.
      - "How Japan Fights,", April 22
      - Statement relating to China, September 17
        Typescript.
      - "How Must We Deal with Japan After the War to Win the Peace?,", October 7
        Typescript and correspondence.
      - "Equal Treatment of China,", November 16
      - "American-Chinese Friendship in World Peace,", November 20
      - Statement relating to the Cairo conference, December 4
        Typescripts.
    - Asian immigration (Box-folder 33: 13)
      - Statement in Congress
      - "Should We Repeal the Chinese Exclusion Laws Now?,", September 2
        Typescripts and printed copy.
      - "Do We Believe Today in our Historic American Principles--Freedom and Equality?,", October 20
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 33: 14)
      Typescript and printed copies of statements. Includes material relating to post-war industrial conversion, reciprocal trade, and consumer subsidies.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 34: 1)
      - General, untitled
      - "What Future for a United Nations Organization?,", March 29
      - "After Victory--What?,", August 11-29
        Typescript and printed copy.
      - "How [to] Achieve Security for America,", September 21
  - 1944
    - General
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - Untitled statement
      - "Iran Gives up Opium"
      - "Our Job in the Pacific,", January 8-10
      - "Tribute to Sun Yat-Sen,", February 18
      - "The Importance to America of Eliminating the Opium Evil Now,", February 21
      - "The Strategy of an International Attack Upon the Opium Evil Now," Current Religious Thought, October
      - Statement on Sino-American relations, October 5
      - Statement on the Stilwell mission to China, November 2
        Clippings.
      - Letter to the Editor, St. Louis Post-Dispatch, December
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 34: 5)
      Typescript, printed copy, notes, and a letter. Includes material relating to socialized medicine.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 34: 6)
      - General
        Citations and a typescript.
      - "What Price Peace,", February 24
      - Congressional letter to Cordell Hull relating to post-war foreign aid, March 24
      - "Do We Have a Positive Foreign Policy Now?,", April 13
      - "Post-War Planning,", April 21
      - Memorandum on a visit to England, August
      - Remarks on Hays-Judd resolution, September-December
  - Politics, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 34: 7)
    Typescripts, printed copies, notes, clippings, and correspondence.
  - 1945
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 34: 8)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - Asia and China
      - General (Box-folder 34: 11)
        Brief statements, broadcast script, typescripts, clippings, notes, and correspondence.
      - "What Is Ahead in Asia," (Box-folder 34: 12)
      - "What Goes on in China,", February 9-15 (Box-folder 34: 12)
        Typescripts and clipping.
      - "How Can Unity be Achieved in China?,", February 22 (Box-folder 34: 13)
        Typescripts and printed copy. Also includes correspondence, clippings, background material, press releases, printed material, bulletins, and speeches by others (including Agnes Smedley).
      - "What Is the Truth about China?,", March 15 (Box-folder 35: 1)
        Printed copies and correspondence.
      - "The People of China,", April 23 (Box-folder 35: 2)
      - "China and the United States--A Challenge to Partnership,", May (Box-folder 35: 3)
        Printed copy, typescripts, and notes.
      - "What Should be Our Policy in China?,", December 27 (Box-folder 35: 4)
        Typescripts, proofs, printed copy, and correspondence.
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 35: 5)
      Typescripts and printed copies of statements. Includes material relating to the armed services, medical personnel, labor, and employment.
    - Foreign affairs
      - General, brief statements (Box-folder 35: 6)
      - "Our Prospects for Peace,", March 10 (Box-folder 35: 7)
      - "Shall We Accept the San Francisco Charter?,", June 28 (Box-folder 35: 8)
        Typescripts, press release, and correspondence.
  - Labor, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 35: 9)
    Typescripts and printed copies. Statements relating to the Federal Mediation Act and a congressional letter to President Truman; also includes a response to a column by Drew Pearson.
  - 1946
    - General
      - Fragment and correspondence (Box-folder 35: 10)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 35: 11)
      - Inserts in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 35: 12)
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 35: 13)
      - Statement on military aid to China, January 9
      - "The Outlook in Asia,", March 4
      - "Manchurian Manifesto,", May 17
      - "Our Policy in China,", May 25
      - "Keys to the Chinese Puzzle," The Rotarian, June
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 35: 14)
      Typescripts and clipping of statements. Primarily relates to price controls.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 35: 15)
      Typescript and printed copy. Statements on a loan to Great Britain and atomic energy.
    - Politics (Box-folder 35: 16)
      Typescripts, printed copy, and notes.
  - 1947
    - General
      - Newsletter, correspondence, clipping, and a list (Box-folder 36: 1)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 36: 2)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 36: 4)
      - General, brief statements
      - "The Significance for America of Events in Asia,", January 5
      - "Blunder Out of China,", July 26
      - Report to the Foreign Affairs Committee (?), November 11
        Notes.
      - "Interim Aid to China,", December
      - Statements relating to aid to China, December 5 and 11
      - "Why Help China?,", December 17
      - Statement relating to General Feng Yu-Hsiang, December 19
        Typescript and press release.
    - Domestic affairs, 1947 (Box-folder 36: 5)
      Typescripts and printed copies. Includes material relating to the National Security Act and compulsory health insurance.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 36: 6)
      - Remarks during the debate on the bill to aid Greece and Turkey, March-May
        Printed copy and notes.
      - "Shall We Continue the International Information and Educational Exchange Program?,", June 6
      - "Which Way Toward Peace?,", Fall
      - Statement on foreign aid, December 8
  - Statements relating to the United Nations, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Asia and China, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 36: 8)
    Speech notes.
  - Asian immigration, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 36: 9)
    Typescripts, printed copies, press release, and notes. Includes remarks by Joseph Grew and others.
  - 1948
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 36: 10)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 36: 11)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 36: 12)
    - Asia and China
      - "What Should We Do in China Now?,", January 6 (Box-folder 36: 13)
        Typescript, printed copies, correspondence, and printed material.
      - "America's Stake in the Far East,", January 30 (Box-folder 36: 14)
      - Congressional question and answer session with George Marshall, February 20
      - Statements, March 23, 31 and June 19
        Printed copies. Includes remarks by General Claire Chennault.
      - "The Chinese Dilemma,", November 21
        Transcript of a radio discussion with John K. Fairbank.
      - Statements, November 30 and December 18
        Typescripts and a printed copy.
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 36: 15)
      Typescripts and printed copies. Includes material relating to price supports, drafting doctors, and government operation.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 36: 16)
      - "What Shall We Do about the Marshall Plan?,", February 19
      - "America's Expanding International Role,", February 22
      - Statement relating to the Marshall Plan, March 24
      - "How Can We Preserve Peace and Freedom Now?,", April 13
        Typescript and printed copies.
      - "Why Join the World Health Organization?,", May 28
      - "Building the New World,", May 30
      - "The War of Ideas in Europe and Asia,", June 19